# MICHELLE MCLANE BROWNLEE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### PERSONAL PROFILE

After spending many years passionately working as a social worker and counselor to advocate and provide services for the most vulnerable populations in our society, I took time off to raise my children. During that time, I added to my creative skills by opening a small pottery studio in my home. Now that I am ready to return to the workforce, I decided to take my creative skills and combine them with my people skills and problem solving skills. Nashville Software School Full Stack Web Development 6 month boot camp seemed like the perfect way to blend all of my strengths.

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

Cell: 615-717-7711
linkedin.com/in/michellemclane-brownlee/
mclanebrownlee@gmail.com
mbrowlee.github.io/Michelle
1609 Appaloosa Ct
Spring Hill, TN 37174

### CAREER HISTORY

### **Full Stack Software Developer**

Nashville Software School April - September 2020

- Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp
- Individual and team-based projects
- Fully remote
- Single page applications using SCRUM methodology and version control with Git and GitHub
- Technologies include: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, and Python/Django.

### **Mental Health - Juvenile Justice Liaison**

Allegheny County Dept of Human Services 2005-2007

- Coordinated between mental health and juvenile justice systems
- Put systems in place to prevent juvenile justice being the default entry point for juveniles into the mental health system
- · Created additional access points to MH
- Implemented a screening tool to help divert juveniles from the justice system to treatment when appropriate.
- Headed multi-agency task force

### **Crisis Counseling Team Leader**

Allegheny County Dept of Human Services

- Worked in conjunction with FEMA teams to assist community members recover after catastrophic flood
- Headed up the mental health crisis counseling teams
- Worked in variety of community settings
- Conducted support group meetings, mental health wellness checks, and home visit support in worst impacted communities
- Supported other crisis counselors on my team

### **Children's Services File Auditor**

Allegheny County Dept of Human Services 2004

 Reviewed children services case files for billing reconciliation to recover lost revenues.

# MICHELLE MCLANE BROWNLEE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

Cell: 615-717-7711
linkedin.com/in/michellemclane-brownlee/
mclanebrownlee@gmail.com
mbrowlee.github.io/Michelle
1609 Appaloosa Ct
Spring Hill, TN 37174

### Partial Hospitalization Group Therapist, Case Manager

Community Mental Health Care, Inc 2001-2002

- Co-facilitated partial hospitalization groups for middle school children and pre-school children with severe behavioral issues
- Completed intakes and treatment plans for children and families receiving counseling services
- Maintained weekly contact through home visits and school visits to facilitate care across environments
- Extensive charting to track progress.

### **Drug & Alcohol Counselor, Legal Advocate**

Harbor House, Inc 2000-2001

- Attended all municipal court arraignments to offer information and support to domestic violence and sexual assault victims
- Advocated for and supported shelter and halfway house clients in all legal hearings
- Assisted with pro se filings for protection orders
- Community and police training on domestic violence laws and protection orders
- Wrote and managed grants
- Facilitated domestic violence support groups for victims
- Facilitated groups sessions and conducted individual sessions for clients in drug and alcohol recovery.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Nasyhille Software School**

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp

### **Walsh University**

Master's Program in Counseling and Human Development

### **Ohio University**

B.A. Psychology major & Political Science